actebis.com 2014-06-28

# ALSO Holding AG - Data privacy statement

**1\. General**

We are pleased to welcome you to our website. Please read the data privacy statement in this document. By using this website you agree to comply with these terms.

 **2\. Data privacy**

  1. When you visit the ALSO website, general information is collected automatically (in other words, no registration is necessary), but is treated anonymously. The web servers we use store some data by default (e.g. the name of your Internet service provider, the website from which you accessed our site, websites that you visit directly from our site and your IP address). This information is also evaluated anonymously. It is used for the sole purpose of improving the appeal, content and functionality of our website. If data is sent to external service providers, we have technical and organizational measures in place to ensure that data privacy regulations are observed.
  2. ALSO is committed to the responsible use of personal data. We comply strictly with legal provisions when collecting, processing and using data. For certain processes (e.g. participation in competitions, contact with us, submission of application documents, use of the protected area of the site, etc.) you knowingly provide us with personal information. You therefore agree that ALSO may use your personal data to process the respective business transaction, use your address and order data for marketing purposes, and that it may make this information available to third parties or other companies within the ALSO Group. If third party providers gain access to this information, your personal data will always be subject to the privacy and protection policies outlined in the relevant contracts and purpose limitations.
  3. We store personal data for as long as is necessary to provide the service that you have requested or consented to, provided there are no legal obligation to the contrary, such as commercial or statutory fiscal retention periods.
  4. ALSO has technical and organizational security measures in place to protect your data from manipulation, loss, destruction and access by unauthorized persons. These measures are updated and optimized in line with technological developments. Your personal data is encrypted and transferred via the Internet from your computer to our server and vice versa. The actual level of data encryption is sometimes dependent on your computer. You should use the latest version of your browser to ensure that your data is protected by 128-bit encryption.
  5. Cookies are pieces of information stored by web servers in your computer's browser so that you can be identified when you visit the website again. When you use our website, we only store cookies on the hard drive of your computer that are relevant for your visit to our website. The sole purpose of these cookies is to control connection, facilitate navigation and ensure that your visit to our website is a user-friendly experience. Cookies "remember" certain settings during a session, saving you having to repeat then each time you visit the site. In the latest browser versions, you have the option of setting a warning message if a web server wants to place a cookie on your computer. You can either accept or reject cookies. A cookie is also created if you work with Smart Login (and have activated it yourself) to access password-protected areas. Smart Login allows you to access protected areas without entering login details; your login data is stored in the cookie. ALSO stores all data collected using cookies in a non-personalized format.
  6. You have the right to check and/or amend all your personal data that we have stored on our servers. You must send a request in writing to the address provided on the Contact page.

**3\. Changes**

ALSO retains the right to make changes to this data privacy statement or the content of the website at any time without notice, particularly in relation to products, product specifications, services, prices and/or availability. 

**Dated May 2013**
